

## Jhonatan Antonio Montilla Montañez

Master in Big Data & Business Intelligence, Master of Business Administration (MBA) and, Industrial Engineer

### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Professional holds professional twenty years' experience in several types of industries, he acquired knowledge and skills as a data analyst and data engineering through Big Data and BI master, he developed and managed project distinct types such as telecommunications, software development, audiovisual platforms, and construction project management.

### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

jhonmont@gmail.com



https://cl.linkedin.com/in/jhonmont



https://twitter.com/jhonmont

POSTS / PORTFOLIO



https://jhonmont.github.io

# Tools / Level 1 2 3 4 Power BI Python R SQL, (Server & MySQL) No SQL, (MongoDB) HDFS (Spark, Pyspark) Tableau QlickView JavaScript

### **LANGUAGES**

- English, written and spoken professional proficiency
- Spanish, maternal language

### **KNOWLEDGE**

Project development and management processes under PMI methodologies, agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban. Statistical models' creation for events predictions in R language, neural networks creations using machine learning techniques using Python language, handling data from HDFS system (Hadoop) using Spark (Pyspark), data analysis and visualization through Microsoft Power BI and Tableau.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Project Manager at Banco Estado / Tata Consultancy Services / Data Projects / Chile
January 2023 - Mar 2023 | Project closure collaboration process for data ingest automatization from different sources through an ETL solution development in Python, and Power BI data visualization reports generation.

Data Engineer at Citibank / Tata Consultancy Services / Data Projects / Chile

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 | Data ingest processes automation Cloudera on premise server through UrbanCode Deploy and Autosys, HDFS (Hadoop) handling with Pyspark code for prediction machine learning models (Python's Sckit-Learn library) connection, and Python functions development for Tableau data visualization through hyperfiles from Hive database.

Data Visualization Engineer at Cencosud / ACL Tecnología / Data Projects / Chile

Jan 2022 – August 2022 | Data analytics and Power BI reports builder using Power Query and advance Data Analysis Expressions (DAX) programming from several data sources such as, SAP, MicroStrategy, Dremio and MinIO from Amazon Elastic Kubernetes.

Data Analyst and Business Intelligence / Freelance / Data Projects / Chile

May 2020 – Dec 2021 | Reports creation in Power BI using ERP Sage 500 (SQL). Prediction and classification model's creation for data inference. Cleaning and analysis of data collection and transformation. Segmentation survey using statistical program language R.

Projects Coordinator / BuildBIM, S.P.A. / Construction Projects / Chile October 2020 – December 2021

Projects Coordinator / PRY Ingeniería, S.A. / Construction Projects / Chile July 2017 – April 2020

Projects Coordinator / AEC Resources / Construction Projects / Argentina

January 2015 – Jun 2017 | Responsible for reviewing and estimating contract scopes, review of architectural, structural and MEP models for the development of coordinated BIM models for the construction industry.

Project Manager / Strix Technologies, C.A. / Software development / Venezuela

January 2012 - December 2014 | Responsible for being an integral part of the strategy and development, in the design, prototyping and programming processes, supervising team members (developers), establishing team procedures and processes following project management standards.

Post-grades Professor / UNIMET / Academic Teaching / Venezuela

January 2011 - December 2011 | Project management processes professor, professional project management tools in academic specialization and master's programs.

Project Financial Accountant / Nokia / Telecommunications / Venezuela

January 2002 - December 2010 | Responsible for executing accounting and financial activities, analyzing the economic stability of the company's projects and providing financial information (on costs, productivity, margins and project expenses) that allow the board of directors to make budget and investment decisions.

# **EDUCATION**

Master Big Data & Business Intelligence / Isabel I University (Structuralia) / Spain / Online. - September 2019 – February 2021

*Master of Business Administration, MBA / Metropolitana University / Venezuela / Face-to-face.*- January 2006 – December 2007

Industrial Engineer / José María Vargas University / Venezuela / Face-to-face. - January 1995 — December 2000